import 'package:dzidzai_mobile/models/grammar/grammar_exercise.dart';

final List<GrammarExerciseModel> nounQuestions = [
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Making airline (reserve) is mostly done online today.",
    answer: "Reservations",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'reserve' is 'reservation'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Make sure your (arrive) at the airport is at least two hours before the depature of your flight.",
    answer: "Arrival",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'arrive' is 'arrival' and 'depart' is 'departure'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "I will buy loaves of fresh bread from the (bake).",
    answer: "Bakery",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'bake' is 'bakery'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The (divide) of land for resettlement in Zimbabwe has been going on for a few years now.",
    answer: "Division",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'divide' is 'division' and 'resettle' is 'resettlement'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The (confuse) about who would speak at the meeting has been cleared up.",
    answer: "Confusion",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'confuse' is 'confusion'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "The (happy) of the people is all that should matter to the president of any country.",
    answer: "Happiness",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'happy' is 'happiness'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Zimbabweans were oppressed under (colonial).",
    answer: "Colonialism",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'colonial' is 'colonialism'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "People have much more (mobile) these days than they did in the past.",
    answer: "Mobility",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'mobile' is 'mobility'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "Can you explain the (useful) of a mobile phone to me?",
    answer: "Usefulness",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'useful' is 'usefulness'.",
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: "rewriteSentence",
    question: "There was great (curious) surrounding the visit of the president of China.",
    answer: "Curiosity",
    instructions: "Change the verbs and adjectives in brackets to suitable nouns.",
    feedback: "The noun form of 'curious' is 'curiosity'.",
  ),

  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'Because of her age, she was not (illegible / eligible) for the competition.',
    options: ['illegible', 'eligible'],
    answer: 'eligible',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "eligible," which means qualified or allowed to do something.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'Danai’s handwriting is sometimes (illegible / eligible).',
    options: ['illegible', 'eligible'],
    answer: 'illegible',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "illegible," which means not clear enough to be read.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'Shops (loose / lose) a lot of money through shoplifting.',
    options: ['loose', 'lose'],
    answer: 'lose',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "lose," which means to be deprived of something.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'A march by the drum majorettes will (proceed / precede) the major’s speech.',
    options: ['proceed', 'precede'],
    answer: 'precede',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "precede," which means to come before something in time.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'To get to the mine, (proceed / precede) along this road.',
    options: ['proceed', 'precede'],
    answer: 'proceed',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "proceed," which means to move forward or continue.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The (immigration / emigration) department is responsible for people coming into the country.',
    options: ['immigration', 'emigration'],
    answer: 'immigration',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "immigration," which refers to people entering a country.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The newspaper published a short (except / excerpt) from the novel.',
    options: ['except', 'excerpt'],
    answer: 'excerpt',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "excerpt," which means a small part of a text.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The new cabinet was (formally / formerly) sworn in.',
    options: ['formally', 'formerly'],
    answer: 'formally',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "formally," which means done in accordance with rules.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'Anna, the new hairdresser, (formally / formerly) worked as a waitress.',
    options: ['formally', 'formerly'],
    answer: 'formerly',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "formerly," which means previously.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The villagers started a (conversation / conservation) project to stop siltation of the river.',
    options: ['conversation', 'conservation'],
    answer: 'conservation',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "conservation," which means the preservation of resources.',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'I wonder (weather/ whether) the environment will be fine today. I left my jersey at home.',
    options: ['weather', 'whether'],
    answer: 'whether',
    feedback: 'The correct words are "whether" (indicating a choice) and "weather" (referring to atmospheric conditions).',
  ),
  GrammarExerciseModel(
    type: 'mcq',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct word to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The union urged companies to (raise / rise) their salaries.',
    options: ['raise', 'rise'],
    answer: 'raise',
    feedback: 'The correct word is "raise," which means to increase.',
  ),
];
